[music]
Hello everyone and welcome to English Pod.
My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and as you
probably notice on our website this is
one of many different parts of a series
all about having an interview in English.
This is a job interview and at this
point we're at about part seven.
That's right.
So today what we're going to talk about is
the key question whenever you're
having a job interview is they ask you to
describe your key strengths and this is
our word for vocabulary preview today so
let's take a look at it. Very capillary
preview. Okay so you might have heard
the words strength before this is
something that you're good at and so key
strength or key strengths plural
would be things that you think are most
important about you as far as the
things that you do well. That's right so as
we mentioned your boss or your potential
boss might ask you to describe your
key strengths so you're going to
mention a lot of adjectives positive
adjectives saying how how good of a worker
you are so why don't we listen to our
dialogue let's see what
Rebecca has to say about her
key strengths and we'll
look at those in a little bit.
Okay Rebecca now you've given me a good
idea of your work and academic background
but what about you as a person how
do you describe your key strengths? Well
Mr Parsons as I mentioned before and
someone who needs new challenges I'm really
focused and hardworking I think my
academic results prove this. Yes true but
how about other personal qualities?
Well I believe I'm a good team player but I
can also work well independently
I'm very enthusiastic and well I hope my
colleagues would agree I'm fun to work
with. What would you say is your most
positive quality? That's a tough question
but I would have to say my passion I'm
really passionate about journalism
and passionate about my career.
All right so she obviously has a lot of
good key strengths why don't we analyze a
couple of those on language takeaway.
Language takeaway. So one of the first
things that Rebecca mentions is that
she's really focused. Okay so this this
word focused what does this mean? All
right so if a person is focused basically
you're saying that you concentrate on
your work. That's right and someone who's
focused might be very good in a
noisy office or in a place that is full of
distractions like you said because they
don't stop their work and think about
the noise or move around or go talk to
people someone who's focused just sits
down and can do a lot of work all at once.
That's right so she describes
herself as focused and hard of working.
So hardworking means basically what
it sounds like that someone works
very hard that means they put in a lot of
hours they can they get their work
done they're really really dependable.
That's right so as you as you can see we
use the word hardworking together so if you
work hard you don't say I work hard.
You can't say that but if you want to use
it as an adjective you
say I am hardworking.
The opposite of
course would be lazy.
That's right okay so we're focused
we're hardworking and she also said
that she is a good team player. Okay
this is a really key phrase here because
it's something that employers
so people who are hiring new staff
like to look out for because most jobs
you don't work alone you work with other
people and so a team player
is someone who works well
in a group or works well with others.
That's right so a team player
everyone wants to have a good team
player working for their team for their
company and apart from being
a good team player you also
want to be enthusiastic.
That's right so this means that you are
interested in what you
do you are excited about it.
It's not like oh god I have to do
this report it's like oh wow I get to do
this report I'm enthusiastic I'm really
interested I'm going to put a lot of
energy into it.
That's right okay so an enthusiastic person
not only can be about working you
can be enthusiastic about anything about
I don't know painting your
house about going on a trip.
Exactly enthusiastic. All right and
our last word for language take away is
also a good quality to
have if you are passionate
about what you do or what you're doing.
So someone who is passionate about
something really really likes
that thing that means that they
love to do it or love to see it.
Passion is the opposite of not interested
okay so you're really really emotional
excited and interested in something.
That's right so you are passionate
about something. It comes from
the noun passion so you have a passion
for painting. Maybe you love to paint
so you're very passionate about painting.
So a lot of great adjectives there to
describe it yourself in a good
way. Why don't we listen to
our dialogue again and we'll
be back with fluency builder.
Okay Rebecca now you've given me a good
idea of your work and academic background
but what about you as a person?
How would you describe your key strengths?
Well Mr Parsons as I mentioned before
I'm someone who needs new challenges
I'm really focused and hardworking.
I think my academic results prove this.
Yes true but how about
other personal qualities?
Well I believe I'm a good team player
but I can also work well independently.
I'm very enthusiastic and well I
hope my colleagues would agree
and fun to work with. What would
you say is your most positive quality?
Hmm that's a tough question
but I would have to say my passion.
I'm really passionate about journalism
and passionate about my career.
All right so on fluency builder today
we've picked out three key phrases.
Let's take a look at the
first one when Rebecca
said I'm someone who
needs new challenges.
Okay so this structure I'm someone
who is something that you hear a lot of
and you can actually
fill in the end of that
sentence with a number
of different phrases.
So in here we heard I'm someone
who needs new challenges.
We could also say I'm
someone who needs structure.
All right so we can also change
the verb right from needs to.
I'm someone who likes a
challenge or maybe Tracy
is someone who
requires a lot of attention.
All right so this is a way to
introduce a characteristic of yourself.
So you're telling people
something about yourself.
Okay very good. So moving on we
also saw that Rebecca said that she is
fun to work with. I'm fun to work with.
Okay so let's just treat
this like a little fixed phrase.
We say this about
people all the time.
He's fun to work with.
She's fun to work with or
this group is really fun to work with.
They're all really fun to work with.
So that means that it's not
serious that you really enjoy doing it.
So it's a little fixed
phrase that you can use
to say that you know
it's nice to work with
with Rebecca or that she's very you
know not serious not a mean person.
That's right. And
finally we have a phrase
at the end Rebecca
gets a here's a question.
She thinks it's very difficult.
She calls it a tough question.
And so a tough question is
something that is very hard to answer.
That's right.
She says hmm that's a tough question.
So she's basically acknowledging
the fact that the question is difficult.
A tough question. Now we can
combine this word tough with other things.
That's right.
You can say it's a tough situation.
That means it's a hard
situation to handle.
You could also say he's
having a tough time.
That means that right
now in his lives there
are many things that
are difficult for him.
And so tough means
difficult or hard or unpleasant.
Okay. Very good. So a
lot of good stuff coming
from Rebecca
mentioning all the positive
things about her. Why don't we
listen to our dialogue one last time?
Okay Rebecca. Now you've given me a good
idea of your work and academic background.
But what about you as a person?
How would you describe your key strengths?
Well, Mr. Parsons. As I mentioned before,
I'm someone who needs new challenges.
I'm really focused and hard working.
I think my academic results prove this.
Yes, true.
But how about other personal qualities?
Well, I believe I'm a good team player.
But I can also work well independently.
I'm very enthusiastic
and well, I hope my
colleagues would agree.
I'm fun to work with.
What would you say is
your most positive quality?
That's a tough question. But I
would have to say my passion.
I'm really passionate about journalism
and passionate about my career.
All right. So talking
about key strengths, I
think it's always difficult
to talk about yourself
and still sound a
little bit humble. Right?
To not sound like arrogant,
like saying I'm the best.
Right. Well, that's
the key here.
I think you want to say really
good things about yourself
because you're a
salesperson and you're
selling your personality.
But at the same time,
you don't want to sound like a jerk. Like,
I'm the best. I'm so smart. I'm so clever.
That's a little bit off putting. It
makes people uncomfortable.
So I think the
trick is a balance.
Right. And I guess if you
use words such as this,
like, you know, I'm
focused. I'm hard of working.
I'm independent. I
have a passion for this.
It makes you sound like,
you know, like you're a
really good worker,
but you're not arrogant.
You're not saying, oh, well,
you know, I'm the best of
what I do or something
like that. Right.
So you're basically
saying these are my skills.
But, you know, obviously, I'm not the
only person who has these great skills.
That's right. Okay. So that's all the
time we have for today. Be sure to join us
next week. We're also
going to have kind of part
two of this when we talk
about our weaknesses.
So this, this time we talked about our
strengths, then we'll talk about weaknesses.
That's right. So we hope that you will
check out our website, Englishpad.com.
If you have questions or
comments, leave them there for
us. And we'll be in
touch very soon. All right.
We'll see you guys there. Bye. Bye.